Arghya Chakrabarty

Development, design & architecture consultant - intelligent systems

chakrabar@live.com

Summary

10 years of experience in the area of intelligent software and full-stack web application development, with emphasis on great design, high performance and solid security. Have developed application in e-commerce, Health Care, Insurance (Life, Annuities, Property), Telecom domains, for Product Development & Services Provider companies.

Specialities: Design and development of intelligent, high performance, secure and maintainable systems.

https://stackoverflow.com/users/2563833/arghya-c

Experience

Technical Delivery Manager at Accolite

January 2016 - Present

Built multiple small and medium size technical teams from ground up. Teams building enterprise applications, web applications, automation tools, reporting tools - all built from scratch.

I'm working with the teams on better architecture, maintainable design, standards & best practices.

Development Lead at BT

November 2013 - Present

Associate Technical Delivery Manager at Accolite

October 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Writing the e-commerce platform for one of world's leading telecom provider, for their corporate customers. The system is built as SaaS, bases on SOA & with multiple front ends for end users, corporate and agents. Worked on the user-profile-management and order-tracking modules of end user site.

- Development lead, designing & developing an intelligent e-commerce system.
- Designing with performance and maintainability as priority, developing for ease of use.
- Writing tools to continuously improve process and automate complex workflows.
- Creating features & re-writing and refactoring older modules with MVC, REST, AngularJS to improve modularity, performance, maintainability and faster deployments.
- Creating user interface that is responsive (RWD), fluid and intuitive for pure user delight.
- Responsible for quality deliverables, with enhanced productivity, testability and ensuring reliable test coverage and green build all the time.

Senior Software Engineer at ABCO Advisory Services India Private Ltd (Affiliate of The Advisory Board Company)

December 2010 - October 2013 (2 years 11 months)

Worked as a part of development team responsible for Ambulatory module of 'Crimson Continuum of Care' & 'Crimson Clinical Advantage' products of The Advisory Board Company. These are business intelligence applications with analytic support to help health care systems manage their system and data, record statistics, analyse results to perform better, provide continuous care and grow their business.

Developed analytic engine, web interface & ETL tools that loads large health care data into data store, runs analytic and produces intelligent insights in smart human readable formats.

Programmer Analyst at Cognizant Technology Solutions

November 2007 - December 2010 (3 years 2 months)

Worked mainly as mid-level software developer building application core, database layer and basic UI for web based insurance applications.

Worked on multiple technology stacks like Mainframes, COBOL, PL/I, Progress4GL, Dot NET etc. Involved in all phases of development from requirement modelling to deployment. Was responsible for developing core business engine for multiple projects. Also worked as insurance product consultant and trainer.

Education

West Bengal University of Technology

B.Tech, Electronics & Communication Engineering, 2003 - 2007

Activities and Societies: Cultural organization, Departmental sports management, Placement cell **Jadavpur Vidyapith**

High School, Physics Chemistry Mathematics Statistics Literature, 1995 - 2003

Activities and Societies: Quiz team, Event organization team

Arghya Chakrabarty

Development, design & architecture consultant - intelligent systems

chakrabar@live.com



Contact Arghya on LinkedIn